# Henrik Wilhelmsen

## **SUMMARY**

Henrik is a technical animator and game developer with over 7 years of experience working with animation in games.

As a technical animator on several projects at Noid and Ubisoft Stockholm, he has worked with animation tooling and pipeline development, prototyping and building tools with Python and PySide targeting both standalone apps and DCC tools like Blender, Motionbuilder and Maya.

Additionally, he has experience with rigging and implementation of characters and animation, with both internal game-engines, Unity and Unreal engine.

As narrative animator on Avatar: Frontiers of Pandora and Rage 2, he gained experience working with in-game cinematics, narrative animation and dialogue systems.

Henrik also has a lot of experience working with motion capture, from getting into the suit himself with Xsens, planning and directing multi-actor shoots at both internal and external studios, assembly and re-targeting, animation cleanup, all the way to final implementation in-engine.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Noid - Technical Animator

SEPTEMBER 2023 - DECEMBER 2024

#### **Ubisoft Stockholm** - Technical Animator

SEPTEMBER 2021 - September 2023

#### **Ubisoft Stockholm** - Animator

JANUARY 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2021

# **Avalanche Studios, Stockholm** – Experienced Animator

APRIL 2017 - DECEMBER 2018

### **Avalanche Studios, Stockholm** — Junior Animator

APRIL 2017 - APRIL 2018

# **EDUCATION**

INN University, Hamar Norway - Bachelor's degree, Animation
AUGUST 2012 - JUNE 2015

# **SOFTWARE AND TECHNOLOGIES**

- Python
- Blender
- Autodesk Maya
- Autodesk Motionbuilder
- PySide/PyQt
- USD
- Git and Gitlab CI/CD
- Linux and WSL
- Unity
- Unreal Engine
- Nvidia Omniverse